Finding Aid for Media Resources Center (University of Michigan) records, 1948-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Administrative Records
  - Berentson Memorial Broadcasting Award 1968-1969, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Broadcast Committee
    The Broadcasting Committee series (1 ft.) includes minutes, correspondence, and reports of the committee which oversaw radio and television broadcasting at the university. Initially this committee dealt almost exclusively with television broadcasting. Following a reorganization of broadcasting administration in 1958, the committee took on greater responsibility for supervision of radio broadcasting. The files contain information on the development of television broadcasting policy and programming, the role of the Television Center as a service unit for the university, expansion of television facilities, the founding of student radio station WCBN-FM in 1972 and the ensuing controversy with Eastern Michigan University's WEMU over frequency allocation, and the operation of WUOM and WCBN.
    The series is arranged variously by calendar or academic year with minutes, correspondence, and reports interfiled in a single sequence. This series seems to have been the principle administrative file of TVC directors Garrison and Schumacher. This series is continued by the Remley, 1980-1987, series which was the main administrative file of Fred Remley, Schumacher's successor as head of Michigan Media.
    - 1950 1952 (Box 1)
    - 1953 (Box 1)
    - 1954 (Box 1)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 1)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 1)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 1)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 1)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 1)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 1)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 1)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 1)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 1)
    - 1964-1966 (Box 1)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 1)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 1)
    - 1968-1970 (Box 1)
    - 1971 (Box 1)
    - 1972 (Box 1)
    - 1972-Political Broadcasts (Box 1)
    - 1973 (Box 1)
    - 1974 (Box 2)
    - 1975 (Box 2)
    - 1976 (Box 2)
    - 1977 (Box 2)
    - 1978 (Box 2)
  - Remley Files
    - 1980 (Box 27)
    - 1981 (Box 27)
    - 1982 (Box 27)
    - 1983 (Box 27)
    - 1984 (Box 27)
    - 1985 (Box 27)
    - 1986, 2 folders (Box 27)
    - 1987 (Box 27)
    - 1988 (Box 27)
    - Articles 1961-1987 (Box 27)
  - Budget Material
    The Budget Materials (.5 ft.) include background files on budget requests and planning, 1954-1957 and 1968-1985; financial reports and audits, 1976-1985; staff and payroll records, 1950-1972; and the "Holbrook File," 1982-1985, concerning budget cuts and the downsizing of Michigan Media. The Unit Review series includes correspondence, minutes of the review committee, reports prepared by Michigan Media, the report to the Vice President for Academic Affairs (VPAA) from the Committee to Review Michigan Media and the report of the VPAA to the Budget Priorities Committee. The Vice President for Academic Affairs correspondence contains memoranda on a variety of administrative and policy matters, in particular the downsizing of Michigan Media in 1981-82 and the Unit review of 1986. Some VPAA correspondence is also filed in the Broadcasting Committee and Remley series.
    - 1968 (Box 2)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 2)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 2)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 2)
    - 1981-1982 (Budget Cuts) (Box 2)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 2)
    - Financial Reports and Audits
      - 1955 1976-1982 (Box 2)
      - 1982-1985 (Box 2)
    - Five Year Plans 1972-1979 (Box 2)
    - Brinkerhoff Report 1983-1986 (Box 2)
    - Hayes Salary Study 1972 (Box 2)
    - Holbrook File
      - Budget Cuts 1981-1985 (Box 2)
      - "Innovators Reports," 1980-1986 (Box 2)
    - Staff/Payroll Records 1950-1972 (Box 2)
  - Cable Television
    Cable Television files (3 folders) contain information on university wide policies on development of cable television capabilities and the university's relation to local and statewide cable systems. The Yearly Summaries, 1950/51-1958/59, provide fairly detailed information on the production and distribution of television programs.
    - General 1968-1977 (Box 2)
    - Committee on the Future of Educational Television 1971 (Box 2)
    - University Ad Hoc Committee on Cable TV 1973 (Box 2)
  - Channel 31 (Ann Arbor) 1979 (Box 2)
  - Corporation for Public Broadcasting Reports 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports 1953-1958 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Stipends 1954-1979 (Box 3)
  - Film and Video Library Transfer 1987 (Box 3)
  - Medical Color TV
    - 1955-1957 (Box 3)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 3)
    - 1962-1968 (Box 3)
  - Merger of AVEC and TVC 1978, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Phasing Out Michigan Media 1987 (Box 3)
  - Report for Service to Faculty 1986 (Box 3)
  - Unit Review Materials 1986, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Unit Review Reports 1986 (Box 3)
  - Vice President for Academic Affairs, Memos etc.
    - 1976-1980 (Carolyn Davis) (Box 3)
    - 1981-1986 (Mary Ann Swain) (Box 3)
  - Weekly Broadcast Schedule 1973 (Box 3)
  - Weekly Production Reports November 1978-June 1980 (Box 3)
  - Yearly Summaries
    - 1950/1951, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - 1951/1952, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 3)
    - 1953/1954-1956/1957 (Box 3)
    - 1957/1958-1958/1959 (Box 3)
  - Special Projects (Box 4)
    - Advocacy Institute 1968 (Box 4)
    - Challenge of Foreign Policy 1955 (Box 4)
    - Children's TV Workshop Project 1980 (Box 4)
    - Civil Defense 1959 (Box 4)
    - Eli Lilly Grant 1958-1959 (Box 4)
    - ETRC Project 1953-1954 (Box 4)
    - Ford Foundation Workshop (Box 4)
    - Japan Society Film 1960-1961 (Box 4)
    - LS&A Orientation 1960-1964 (Box 4)
    - Magazine Segments 1980-1981 (Box 4)
    - MPATI 1961-1962, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - NAEB Lighting and Staging Workshop 1956 (Box 4)
    - Occupational Health Film 1967-1968 (Box 4)
    - Paso (MPATI Spanish course) 1963 (Box 4)
    - Rose Bowl 1965 (Box 4)
    - "Six Lives" (Indian education project) 1976 (Box 4)
    - Speech Clinic 1963 (Box 4)
    - USIA Band Project 1960 (Box 4)
  - Speeches, Articles, and Special Reports
    - "Current and Future Trends in Audio-Visual Education in the United States," 1975 Fred Remley (Box 4)
    - "Michigan Media Resources Center: A Case Study," 1975 Marcia Jablonski, (student paper) (Box 4)
    - "Some Present and Future Applications of Radio and Television in the University Setting," 1972 Hazen Schumacher (Box 4)
    - "Support for Public TV," 1959 (part of Detroit Area Study) (Box 4)
    - "The New Teaching Technology: Opportunity for Radical Change in University Instruction," Report by the President's Ad Hoc Communications Review Committee 1973 (Box 4)
    - "The Possibilities of Educational Television" Alexander Ruthven 1950 (Box 4)
    - "TV in the University Community," 1968 and other articles by Garnett Garrison, 1951-1953 (Box 4)
- Scripts
  The Scripts series includes all extant scripts for television programs, special project films, and Audio-Visual Education Center productions. The scripts vary from the merest outlines and stage directions to fully worked out dialogue. The scripts, usually bound in volumes, are organized by series and thereunder by chronologically assigned negative number or alphabetically by title. Also included are scripts of several student dramas presented on WWJ-TV by the Speech Department.
  The scripts, in order of arrangement, include:
  Series T, University of Michigan Telecourses broadcast on the original Television Hour, 1950/51-1953/54. Arranged chronologically. (Box 5)
  Series I, Independent, multi-part programs broadcast as part of the University of Michigan Television Hour, 1955-1980. Arranged alphabetically by program title. (Boxes 6-15)
  Series B, Individual Programs of general interest broadcast under the title "Understanding Our World" (UOW). The series was initially broadcast live over WOOD-TV, Grand Rapids, 1952-1953, and later recorded on film or tape and broadcast as part of the UM Television Hour, 1954-1982. Arranged by chronologically assigned negative number with separate sequences for WOOD and Television Hour programs. Some Series B scripts are missing. (Box 17-19)
  Series H, "Michigan Report" 1952-1955. This series was the successor to the "Teletour" portion of the original Television Hour. It was broadcast over WWJ-TV Saturday evenings. Arranged chronologically. (Box 20)
  Series A, "Accent: A Michigan Report" 1955-1961. This series is a continuation of Series H under a new name. Arranged chronologically. (Box 20)
  Special Projects, Scripts for televised programs that were not part of an ongoing series or films not intended for broadcast use. Arranged alphabetically by title. (Boxes 20-22)
  Trigger Films, Scripts and outlines for several trigger films that were not part of an ongoing series. (Box 22)
  Early Television Plays, Scripts of six student plays produced on WWJ-TV by UM students, 1948-1953. (Box 22)
  WPAG-TV, An incomplete set of scripts for several series broadcast from the UM Television Center studio over the Ann Arbor UHF channel, 1954-1957. (Box 24-25)
  AVEC, Scripts for films produced by the University of Michigan Audio-Visual Education Center, ca.1951-1978. Arranged alphabetically by title. (Box 25-26)
  - UM Television Hour (Telecourses)
    - 1950-1951
      - Man in His World: Human Biology, 1-14 (Box 5)
      - Living in the Later Years, 1-7 (Box 5)
      - Photography, 1-7 (Box 5)
      - Lands and Peoples of the Far East, 1-14 (Box 5)
      - Fundamentals of Interior Design, 1-7 (Box 5)
      - Retailing and the Customer, 1-7 (Box 5)
    - 1951-1952
      - Man in His World: Human Behavior, 1-15 (Box 5)
      - Democracy in Action: Parliamentary Procedure, 1-7 (Box 5)
      - Understanding the Child, 1-7 (Box 5)
      - Democracy in Action: Political Parties, 1-15 (Box 5)
      - Understanding Numbers, 1-7 (Box 5)
      - Exploring the Universe, 1-7 (Box 5)
    - 1952-1953
      - Man in His World: Modern Physics, 1-15 (Box 5)
      - Understanding Our Natural Resources, 1-8 (Box 5)
      - Understanding Music, 1-7 (Box 5)
    - 1953-1954
      - Progress of Mankind, 1-15 (Box 5)
      - Creative Artists at Work, 1-8 (Box 5)
      - Food and Nutrition, 1-7 (Box 5)
      - Engineering: Building the Modern World, 1-15 (Box 5)
      - The Growing Baby, 1-8 (Box 5)
      - Lands and Peoples of Latin America, 1-7 (Box 5)
      - Theater Arts, 1-7 (Box 5)
      - American Business, 1-7 (Box 5)
      - Fish and Fishing: In Recreation and Commerce, 1-8 (Box 5)
      - Your Health and Medicine, 1-8 (Box 5)
    - 1954
      - The Teenager: A Study of Adolescent Behavior, 1-15 (Box 5)
      - Our Changing earth, 1-3 (Box 5)
      - Democracy in Action: Political Parties, 1-13 1954 (Box 5)
      - Understanding the Child, 1-7 1954 (Box 5)
      - Understanding Numbers, 1-7 1954 (Box 5)
  - Series I
    - After Eden, 1-15 1968 (Box 6)
    - American Consumer, The, 1-10 1973 (Box 6)
    - American Negro, The, 1-10 1964 (Box 6)
    - American Story Classics, 1-10 1965 (Box 6)
    - Art and the Child, 1-8 1955 (Box 6)
    - Artist at Work, 1-15, 16-30 1973, 1975 (Box 6)
    - Assignment, 1-10 1970 (Box 6)
    - Bell for Freedom, A, 1-7 1956-1957 (Box 6)
    - Black Experience, The, 1-10 1970 (Box 6)
    - Blessings of Liberty, 1-10 1960 (Box 6)
    - Canterbury Tales, 1-10 1967 (Box 6)
    - Challenge of Capitalism, 1-10 1959-1960 (Box 7)
    - Challenge of Foreign Policy, 1-13 1955 (Box 7)
    - Changing Earth, 1-15 1963-1964 (Box 7)
    - Childhood: Worlds to Discover, 1-10 1964 (Box 7)
    - China After Mao, 1-10 1980 (Box 7)
    - China: Background for Discussion, 1-5 1971 (Box 7)
    - China: The Dragon and the Star, 1-10 1959 (Box 7)
    - City Desk, 1-5 1976 (Box 7)
    - City of Time, The, 1-10 1971 (Box 7)
    - Contemporary Dance, 1-8 1971 (Box 7)
    - Conversations With Allen Whiting, 1-5 1979 (Box 7)
    - Creation of Art, The, 1-10 1974 (Box 7)
    - Crime and Justice, 1-10 1973 (Box 7)
    - Dickens World, 1-10 1973 (Box 7)
    - Discovery of Science, The, 1-10 1972 (Box 8)
    - Drawing with Guy Palazzola, 1-15 1970 (Box 8)
    - Ecology: Man and the Environment, 1-15, 1970) (Box 8)
    - Economics: People and Resources, 1-6 1969 (Box 8)
    - Education: Today and Tomorrow, 1-10 1967-1968 (Box 8)
    - Everybody's Business: Challenge of Change, 1-10 1965 (Box 8)
    - Family Living, 1-15 1968 (Box 8)
    - From Haydn to Hi-Fi, 1-8 1956 (Box 8)
    - Frontiers of Health, 1-30 1955-1956 (Box 8)
    - Future Without Shock, 1-10 1975-1980 (Box 8)
    - Genius, 1-20 1957 (Box 8)
    - Geography of Conflict, 1-8 1956 (Box 8)
    - Germany Today, 1-10 1966 (Box 8)
    - Gift of Life, 1-15 1957 (Box 9)
    - Girls and Women, 1-10 1971 (Box 9)
    - Government of Michigan, 1-8 1957 (Box 9)
    - Greek Tragedy on Stage, 1-10 1969 (Box 9)
    - Her Social Security, 1-4 1977 (Box 9)
    - Herodotus: Father of Time, 1-10 1979 (Box 9)
    - Homeric World, 1-15 1968 (Box 9)
    - House Botanist, 1-20 1978 (Box 9)
    - Identity and Conflict, 1-10 1977 (Box 9)
    - Iliad of Homer, The, 1-10 1974 (Box 9)
    - Images of America, 1-15 1963 (Box 9)
    - In-Out-Round About, 1-10 1968 (Box 9)
    - In Performance, 1-4 1979 (Box 9)
    - Inquiring Mind, The, 1-15 1963 (Box 9)
    - Inside Music, 1-10 1978 (Box 9)
    - Insurance, 1-7 1955-1956 (Box 9)
    - Issue at Hand, 1-10 1976 (Box 9)
    - Japan: The Changing Years, 1-10 1960-1961 (Box 9)
    - Know Your Sports, 1-8 1955 (Box 9)
    - Land to be Free, 1-8 1955 (Box 9)
    - Legacy, 1-10 1959 (Box 10)
    - Life, Death, and Taxes, 1-8 1962 (Box 10)
    - Living Language, The, 1-15 1965 (Box 10)
    - Living Past, The, 1-10 1966 (Box 10)
    - Magic Path, The, 1-15 1957 (Box 10)
    - Making of Music, The, 1-17 1962 (Box 10)
    - Malaysia: Crossroads in the Ocean, 1-7 1969 (Box 10)
    - Man and Continent VII, 1-5 1959 (Box 10)
    - Man in the Middle, 1-10 1969 (Box 10)
    - Man the Maker, 1-10 1969 (Box 10)
    - Mansions of Man, 1-10 1957 (Box 10)
    - Many Worlds of India, The, 1-10 1967 (Box 10)
    - Maps: Horizons to Knowledge, 1-5 1980 (Box 10)
    - Marriage, 1-15 1956 (Box 11)
    - Meet the Masters, 5-8 1966 (Box 11)
    - Men of Property, 1-5 1970 (Box 11)
    - Music Shop, 1-20 1974 (Box 11)
    - Nation of Rebels, A, 1-5 1970-1972 (Box 11)
    - Northern Michigan, 1-7 1955 (Box 11)
    - Nuclear Age, 1-15, 1968) (Box 11)
    - Nuclear Power and You, 1-5 1978-1979 (Box 11)
    - Of Greeks and Gods, 1-5 1971 (Box 11)
    - Of Men and Motives, 1-15 1961-1963 (Box 11)
    - Offstage, 1-10 1976 (Box 11)
    - On to Tomorrow, 1-6 1976 (Box 11)
    - Our Aging Society, 1-2 1979 (Box 11)
    - Our Changing Earth, 1-7 1954 (Box 11)
    - Painter's Art, The, 1-10 1962 (Box 11)
    - Painting With Guy Palazzola, 1-10 1967 (Box 11)
    - Pike on Language, 1-5 1977 (Box 11)
    - Planning Your Financial Future, 1-8 1954 (Box 11)
    - Plays of Shakespeare, 1-15 1961 (Box 11)
    - Poets Talking, 1-15 1974 (Box 12)
    - Presidential Campaign, 1-7 1956 (Box 12)
    - Profile of a Nation: France, 1-7 1957 (Box 12)
    - Profile of Space, 1-10 1957 (Box 12)
    - Progress of Man, 1-10 1959 (Box 12)
    - Public Arts, 1-10 1959 (Box 12)
    - Quest for Certainty, 1-20 1963 (Box 12)
    - Quiet Furies, 1-10 1967-1969 (Box 12)
    - Rethinking America, 1-4 1979 (Box 12)
    - River of History, 1-10 1970 (Box 12)
    - Russia: Faces of a Giant, 1-10 1958 (Box 12)
    - Science, Quest and Conquest, 1-20, 1958) (Box 13)
    - Seekers, The, 1-15 1961 (Box 13)
    - Silent Heritage, 1-10 1966 (Box 13)
    - Since You Can't Take It With You, 1-6 1968 (Box 13)
    - Singer's Art, The, 1-14 1972 (Box 13)
    - Social Animal, The, 1-10 1973 (Box 13)
    - Social Security, 1-5 1974 (Box 13)
    - Some Historical Spirits, 1-10 1965 (Box 13)
    - Sounds Into Music, 1-10 1967-1968 (Box 13)
    - Southeast Asia, 1-10 1964 (Box 14)
    - Speak Up, 1-15 1960-1961 (Box 14)
    - Speaking to Others, 1-17 1955 (Box 14)
    - Story of Italy, 1-10 1961-1962 (Box 14)
    - Take as Directed, 1-15 1969-1970 (Box 14)
    - Teenager, The, 1-15 1954 (Box 14)
    - This World of Water, 1-10 1966 (Box 14)
    - Through Children's Eyes, 1-14 1963 (Box 14)
    - Transitions: Caught at Midlife, 1-10 1979-1980 (Box 14)
    - Traumatic Years, 1-2 (Box 14)
    - Twelve Caesars, 1-10 1980 (Box 14)
    - UM 150, 1-9 1966-1967 (Box 15)
    - Understanding Money, 1-7 1971 (Box 15)
    - Unreasonable Men, 1-10 1963-1964 (Box 15)
    - Western Europe, 1-10 1958-1959 (Box 15)
    - Western Way, The, 1-15 1960 (Box 15)
    - Worlds of Abraham Kaplan, 1-11 1971 (Box 15)
    - Worlds of Women, 1-10 1976 (Box 15)
    - Your Child's First Year, 1-10 1958 (Box 15)
  - Series B (Understanding Our World)
    - vol. U1, Spring 1953 (Box 16)
      (1-13 Kalamazoo broadcasts)
    - vol. U3 1952-1953 (Box 16)
      (1-3 Grand Rapids Broadcasts)
    - vol. U4, 1-45 1954-1955 (Box 16)
    - vol. U5, 46-90 1955-1956 (Box 16)
    - vol. U6, 91-135 1955-1957 (Box 16)
    - vol. U7, 136-180 1957-1958 (Box 16)
    - vol. U8, 181-215 1958-1959 (Box 16)
    - vol. U9, 216-240 1958-1959 (Box 16)
    - vol. U10, 241-265 1959 (Box 17)
    - vol. U11, 266-300 1960-1961 (Box 17)
    - vol. U12, 301-331 1961 (Box 17)
    - vol. U13, 332-360 1961-1962 (Box 17)
    - vol. U14, 361-399 1962 (Box 17)
    - vol. U15, 400-430 1962-1963 (Box 17)
    - vol. U16, 431-460 1963-1964 (Box 18)
    - vol. U17, 461-485 1963-1964 (Box 18)
    - vol. U18, 486-516 1964-1965 (Box 18)
    - vol. U19, 517-540 1965-1966 (Box 18)
    - vol. U20, 541-557 1965-1966 (Box 18)
    - vol. U21, 558-582 1966 summer (Box 18)
    - vol. U22, 583-616 1966-1967 (Box 18)
    - vol. U23, 617-662 1967-1968 (Box 18)
    - vol. U24, 663-707 1968-1970 (Box 19)
    - vol. U25, 708-752 1970-1972 (Box 19)
    - vol. U26, 753-796 1971-1974 (Box 19)
    - vol. U27, 797-822 1974-1975 (Box 19)
    - 823-839 1976 (Box 19)
    - 840-848 1977-1978 (Box 19)
    - 849-881 1979-1982 (Box 19)
    - unnumbered 1979 (Box 19)
  - Series H (Michigan Report) 1952-1959
    - Scripts, 2 volumes (Box 20)
  - Series A (Accent)
    - 1-60 1955-1957 (Box 20)
    - 61-100 1957-1958 (Box 20)
    - 101-130 1958-1959 (Box 20)
    - 131-160 1959-1960 (Box 20)
    - 161-195 1960-1961 (Box 20)
  - Special Projects
    - Advocates, The, 1-8 1967-1968 (Box 21)
    - Alumni Fund Film 1956 (Box 21)
    - A.I.D.S. To You (Box 21)
      (Alumni Information Directory System)
    - Basic French Grammar 1970 (Box 21)
    - Basic Operation of MTS 1969 (Box 21)
    - Building Surfaces Thermal Cost-Performance (Box 21)
    - Check Your Speed (Box 21)
    - Civil Advocacy Vignettes, 1-24 1966 (Box 21)
    - Circus in America, 1-3 (Box 21)
    - Concerned Generation, A (Box 21)
    - Conference on Aging 1970 (Box 21)
    - Detroit Public Library 1954 (Box 21)
    - Dorothy Coon Workshop (Box 21)
    - Edible Wild Plants 1978 (Box 21)
    - Festival of Song (Box 21)
    - Gerontology Scenes 1962 (Box 21)
    - Glen Forrester-Niagra Script (Box 21)
    - Grounds Maintenance (Box 21)
    - Great Lakes: No Free Lunch (Box 21)
    - Hagerstown 1958 (Box 21)
    - IBM Punch Card Operation 1967 (Box 21)
    - Idea of Michigan 1962 (Box 21)
    - Inconceivable Commerce, An 1973 (Box 21)
    - Intern 1967 (Box 21)
    - International Year of the Child 1979 (Box 21)
    - ISMR Trigger Films 1970 (Box 21)
    - Many Lives of JQP (John Q. Public) (Box 21)
    - Mathematics, 1-16 1960 (Box 21)
    - Michigan Turnpike Authority 1955 (Box 21)
    - Michigan Week 1960 (Box 21)
    - MPATI (Box 21)
    - Michigras Parade 1956 (Box 21)
    - New Concepts in Housing for the Elderly 1978 (Box 21)
    - Newsreels 1964-1968 (Box 21)
    - O & W Beverage-Energy for Industry (Box 21)
    - Office of Civil and Defense Preparedness (Box 21)
    - Operation Deep Freeze (shot list for six reels of Film File film no. 249, apparently used in Series I program, Man and Continent VII) (Box 21)
    - Painting the Past 1959 (Box 21)
    - Personnel Office 1971 (Box 21)
    - Phoenix Project (Box 21)
    - Pre-Parole Project (Box 21)
    - Prime of Life, The (Box 21)
    - Reality Practice and You (Box 21)
    - Safer World on Wheels, A (HSRI Dedication) (Box 21)
    - Staging 1958 (Box 21)
    - Stanley Quartet South American Tour (Box 21)
    - State and Community Relations (Box 21)
    - Studio Sampler (Box 21)
    - Teaching, Research, Service 1967 (Box 21)
    - Tension Areas (Box 21)
    - They Teach at Michigan 1970 (Box 21)
    - To Your Health 1974 (Box 21)
    - United Campaign Fund Promo 1963 (Box 21)
    - WDIV-TV Magazine Segment (Box 21)
    - We Are Young We Are Black (Box 21)
    - We Came to Ann Arbor (Box 22)
    - Welcome Michigan (Box 22)
    - Years of Glory, Years of Growth (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 22)
  - Trigger Films
    - General (Box 22)
    - Aging (Box 22)
    - Drugs (Box 22)
    - Mental Retardation (Box 22)
    - Teenage Driving (Box 22)
  - Early Television Plays
    - "Mr. Plummerton Finds the Truth" 1948 (Box 22)
    - "Dementia Wilcox" 1948 (Box 22)
    - "Master Pierre Patelin" 1949 (Box 22)
    - "Walls of Glass" 1949 (Box 22)
    - "Arthur Savile's Crime" 1949 (Box 22)
    - "Creatures of Impulse" 1953 (Box 22)
- Brochures and Catalogs
  The Brochures and Catalogs consist of publicity and informational material on the Television Center and individual series or programs. The catalogs are listings, with brief descriptions, of television programs and films available from the Michigan Media film and video library.
  - circa 1951-1984, 4 folders (Box 22)
- Press Releases
  The Press Releases series consists of news releases provided to television stations and the press at the time a program was to be broadcast. They contain brief summaries of the subject matter of the program and usually name the "stars." Arrangement of the press releases is by television series and thereunder chronologically or alphabetically, corresponding to the arrangement of the scripts.
  - Series A (Accent)
    - 1-100 (Box 22)
    - 101-199 (Box 22)
  - Series I
    - A (Box 22)
    - B-C (Box 22)
    - D-E (Box 22)
    - F (Box 23)
    - GH-I (Box 23)
    - J-Mag (Box 23)
    - Mak-Mu (Box 23)
    - N-O (Box 23)
    - P (Box 23)
    - Q-R (Box 23)
    - S (Box 23)
    - T-U (Box 23)
    - V-Z (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous Programs, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Series B (Understanding Our World)
    - 1-100 (Box 23)
    - 101-200 (Box 23)
    - 201-300 (Box 23)
    - 301-400 (Box 23)
    - 401-500 (Box 23)
    - 501-600 (Box 23)
    - 601-700 (Box 23)
    - 701-800 (Box 23)
    - 801-849, 858-870 (Box 23)
  - WPAG-TV 1956-1957
    - General (Box 23)
- Study Guides/Course Syllabi
  The Study Guides/Course Outlines include the supplementary material for the Telecourse programs, 1950-1954 and for three programs in Series I, "Creation of Art," "Dickens' World" and "Music for Metrics."
  - Television Hour 1950-1954 (Box 24)
  - Creation of Art 1975 (Box 24)
  - Dickens' World (Box 24)
  - Music for Metrics 1975 (Box 24)
- Other scripts
  - Radio Scripts
    - "Angell Hall Playhouse," 1951 (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous Scripts circa 1951 (Box 24)
  - WWJ-TV "Down Storybook Lane" (Box 24)
  - WPAG TV
    - Women's Sports Page
      - Oct-Dec 1954 (Box 24)
      - 1955 (Box 24)
      - 1956-1957 (Box 24)
    - Storytime (Box 24)
    - WPAG Scripts 1954-1956, 8 volumes (Box 25)
- Audio-Visual Education Center (AVEC)
  - Filmstrip Scripts (Box 26)
  - Film Scripts
    - Aging: A Modern Social Achievement (1957) (Box 26)
    - Automyocardial Autogenous Skin Grafts (Box 26)
    - Basic Movement Education in England (Box 26)
    - Big Difference, The (1966) (Box 26)
    - Child Amputees (1964) (Box 26)
    - Children with Cleft Palate (1954 ?) (Box 26)
    - Decade of Achievement 1946-1956 (Box 26)
    - Design for Independent Living (Box 26)
    - Digital Engineering Lab (1973) (Box 26)
    - Engineering Centennial-The First Hundred Years (1954) (Box 26)